<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>People on Coder Frontline</title>
    <link>/categories/people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in People on Coder Frontline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 21:50:12 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Zumba helped me become a better Tech Lead</title>
      <link>/how-zumba-helped-me-become-a-better-tech-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 21:50:12 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-zumba-helped-me-become-a-better-tech-lead/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about some of the commonalities between Zumba instructors and Tech Leads in my last post. I have a few more points to add on, which will give you an idea of the multitude of skills required to be either.
Multitasking Zumba instructors are fierce multitaskers. Our main job is to dance to the music so that participants can follow along. But we also need to think ahead to what the next move is because we need to inform the class that the change is coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do Tech Leads and Zumba instructors have in common?</title>
      <link>/what-do-tech-leads-and-zumba-instructors-have-in-common/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 15:25:58 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what-do-tech-leads-and-zumba-instructors-have-in-common/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a part-time Zumba instructor since 2011 and I was a certified Les Mills BodyJam instructor for a few years before that. I recently looked back at my past year being a Tech Lead at Datacom and I can see many similarities with the necessary qualities of being either. I am in a very unique position since I have inhabited both roles, hence I wrote this post to illuminate some of the non-obvious ways a group fitness instructor creates an effective workout session, and how that ties in to be a great Tech Lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Open Door Policy Is Not Enough</title>
      <link>/the-open-door-policy-is-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 13:47:38 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-open-door-policy-is-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>I remember hearing the term open door policy when I joined my first company after university. It was touted as a morale-booster because we are free to bring up any concerns we have with our managers, or even managers higher up the food chain. I remember being impressed by the concept when it was explained to me, but I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to question if the open door policy is doing more harm than good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faking Extroversion: An Introvert&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>/faking-extroversion-an-introverts-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 14:40:01 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faking-extroversion-an-introverts-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was having a drink with a friend I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen in years when he confided that he&amp;rsquo;s having trouble making friends in a new city. He had moved there to be close to his partner, which meant that his social circle was limited to his partner&amp;rsquo;s social circle. This posed a problem for my friend whenever he had relationship issues, as he did not have nearby friends of his own. His main roadblock, he insisted, was his introversion. I can certainly relate to that as I am an introvert myself. However, I recognize the value of having a strong social support network, which inherently requires some extroversion to build. I faced the same issue when I moved to New Zealand alone and had to make a concerted effort to fake extroversion. I decided to share some of my techniques with this friend and it inspired me to write this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Interview Questions #26</title>
      <link>/good-interview-questions-#26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 20:45:24 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/good-interview-questions-#26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve encountered all sorts of interview questions, mostly on the receiving end but some as part of the interviewing team myself. I will elaborate on some good and bad interview questions, at least in my humble opinion. The numbers are random fun – I don’t have 25 other examples on this blog (yet).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Excerpt: Impossible to Ignore</title>
      <link>/book-excerpt-impossible-to-ignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 21:22:03 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/book-excerpt-impossible-to-ignore/</guid>
      <description>Is your presentation impossible to ignore? I’ve sat through many presentations in my lifetime, and I expect to sit through quite a few more before I die. It’s astonishing how many technical presentations are treated as information dumps, with no intention to persuade or get audiences to improve their ways. People get bored, and I frequently see smartphones whipped out in conference rooms. I have been guilty of giving such presentations before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate On-Boarding for Early Success</title>
      <link>/deliberate-on-boarding-for-early-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 10:03:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deliberate-on-boarding-for-early-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On-boarding programmes, also known as induction programmes, are the set of activities designed to get a new hire up and running in the organisation as soon as possible. I discussed a few types of &lt;a href=&#34;/induction-programmes-new-hires/&#34;&gt;induction programmes&lt;/a&gt; last week. I will share my own experiences with on-boarding below, including the elements that go into making an effective plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory on Success - How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big</title>
      <link>/a-theory-on-success-how-to-fail-at-almost-everything-and-still-win-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 04:52:27 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-theory-on-success-how-to-fail-at-almost-everything-and-still-win-big/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Qf49Xg&#34;&gt;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big: Kind of the Story of My Life&lt;/a&gt; is the title of an excellent book about success (or lack thereof!) by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Scott Adams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt; creator and frequent writer on his personal blog. I’ve been an avid reader of his for years, and have read his non-Dilbert fiction books (&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Qf4lWq&#34;&gt;God’s Debris&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1SSEq8P&#34;&gt;The Religion War&lt;/a&gt;) as well. What I enjoy most about Scott’s writing style is the concise manner he puts his points across. It’s an important skill to have when trying to make readers laugh in 3 comic panels, and he puts it to good use in his writing. The following is a brief overview of the key points I took away from his book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
