<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on Coder Frontline</title>
    <link>/categories/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on Coder Frontline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 22:08:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Our Team Brand</title>
      <link>/our-team-brand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 22:08:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/our-team-brand/</guid>
      <description>One of my highlights at work in 2019 was taking the team through a Team Brand exercise. This is a culture definition team activity that I learned from a previous role. It is based on a simple premise: What words do you want other teams to use when describing us?
Team culture fascinates me but it often lives as a vague affirmation that &amp;ldquo;Yes, we want a good culture&amp;rdquo;. How does that translate into meanigful behaviours and actions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Zumba helped me become a better Tech Lead</title>
      <link>/how-zumba-helped-me-become-a-better-tech-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 21:50:12 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-zumba-helped-me-become-a-better-tech-lead/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about some of the commonalities between Zumba instructors and Tech Leads in my last post. I have a few more points to add on, which will give you an idea of the multitude of skills required to be either.
Multitasking Zumba instructors are fierce multitaskers. Our main job is to dance to the music so that participants can follow along. But we also need to think ahead to what the next move is because we need to inform the class that the change is coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chess Master and The Gardener</title>
      <link>/the-chess-master-and-the-gardener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 21:32:57 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-chess-master-and-the-gardener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love listening to podcasts to entertain my commute. I&amp;rsquo;ll at least learn something if I&amp;rsquo;m going to be stuck in traffic 200 hours a year. One of my subscriptions is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-tony-robbins-podcast/id1098413063?mt=2&#34;&gt;Tony Robbins Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, featuring the motivational guru interviewing a myriad of successful individuals. A recent episode that really resonated with me is a chat with General Stanley McChrystal and Chris Fussell, titled “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tonyrobbins.com/podcasts/becoming-extraordinary-leader/&#34;&gt;Becoming an extraordinary leader&lt;/a&gt;“. The interviewees served in the U.S. military for decades and have gained some insights into great leadership. An analogy the General used to describe leadership was the chess master and the gardener.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Things Matter</title>
      <link>/the-little-things-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 16:28:09 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-little-things-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a day off today after a stressful month. So I decided to treat myself to a massage to work out those tense shoulders I&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying around. But I saw something before the massage even started that reaffirmed my belief that the little things matter more than we appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Pride</title>
      <link>/developer-pride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 04:48:12 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/developer-pride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My development manager recently asked us for input on building an engineering culture at work. I semi-coined a new term: developer pride. The term has gotten &lt;a class=&#34;external-link&#34; href=&#34;http://codesqueeze.com/do-managers-prey-on-developer-pride/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;bad rep&lt;/a&gt; in the past, but I want to reclaim it in the same way the LGBT rights movement transformed the word &lt;em&gt;pride&lt;/em&gt; from the negative connotations of being a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_deadly_sins#Pride&#34;&gt;deadly sin&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theallusionist.org/allusionist/pride&#34;&gt;antidote to shame&lt;/a&gt;. So what does developer pride mean to me?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induction Programmes for New Hires</title>
      <link>/induction-programmes-for-new-hires/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 10:23:27 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/induction-programmes-for-new-hires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few tech companies give much thought to formal induction programmes for new employees. It does not seem to give much benefit at first glance, since it happens irregularly. I have experienced both well-structured and informal induction programmes, and I can wholeheartedly say I prefer the former.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisited: Why Care About Culture?</title>
      <link>/revisited-why-care-about-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 11:41:21 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/revisited-why-care-about-culture/</guid>
      <description>This coder is stepping away from the front line for another week while he takes a well-deserved holiday on the Indonesian destination of Bali. Instead, I will link to an article from the archives and add some new thoughts on it.
This week I revisit my post on why we should care about culture. I put forward my argument that we should pay close attention to culture as it affects more than just whether people have work drinks on a Friday afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clash of Culture - MediaWorks and Mark Weldon Part Ways</title>
      <link>/clash-of-culture-mediaworks-and-mark-weldon-part-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 01:00:25 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clash-of-culture-mediaworks-and-mark-weldon-part-ways/</guid>
      <description>A clash of culture happens when cultures don&amp;rsquo;t mesh - and the resulting fireworks can be very dangerous. It gives further reason to care about culture and how one&amp;rsquo;s personal culture can affect the entire organisation. Some choice excerpts from NZ Herald - 4 May 2016 article on Mark Weldon&amp;rsquo;s resignation (all **emphasis **is mine):
 “People in that company actually love that company. The issue for Mark is that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a cultural fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory on Success - How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big</title>
      <link>/a-theory-on-success-how-to-fail-at-almost-everything-and-still-win-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 04:52:27 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-theory-on-success-how-to-fail-at-almost-everything-and-still-win-big/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Qf49Xg&#34;&gt;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big: Kind of the Story of My Life&lt;/a&gt; is the title of an excellent book about success (or lack thereof!) by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Scott Adams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt; creator and frequent writer on his personal blog. I’ve been an avid reader of his for years, and have read his non-Dilbert fiction books (&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Qf4lWq&#34;&gt;God’s Debris&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1SSEq8P&#34;&gt;The Religion War&lt;/a&gt;) as well. What I enjoy most about Scott’s writing style is the concise manner he puts his points across. It’s an important skill to have when trying to make readers laugh in 3 comic panels, and he puts it to good use in his writing. The following is a brief overview of the key points I took away from his book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Care About Culture</title>
      <link>/why-care-about-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 07:43:23 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-care-about-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last 3 posts I have &lt;a href=&#34;/culture-re-introduction/&#34;&gt;re-introduced culture&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/elements-culture-onion/&#34;&gt;explained it as an onion&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;/cultural-web/&#34;&gt;explored the cultural web&lt;/a&gt;. It’s now crunch time – why care about culture at all? Culture is dynamic and monolithic, made up of deeply-held assumptions and embedded in corporate DNA. Many authors have tried to discredit the idea of cultural change as a strategic move. They recommend tailoring strategies and tactics to fit the existing culture instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why care about culture? I will skip the textbook answers this time and share my personal view. I care about culture because it affects how well I can do my job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Web</title>
      <link>/cultural-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 02:35:26 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cultural-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Cultural Web Analysis is another useful tool that helps tease out the constituent parts of an organisation’s culture. It builds upon the &lt;a href=&#34;/elements-culture-onion/&#34;&gt;Onion Model of Culture mentioned previously&lt;/a&gt;, but has more concrete classifications that I found helpful. The Cultural Web was introduced by Gerry Johnson and Kevan Scholes, who were also writers of the excellent Exploring Strategy textbook I used for my Strategic Management course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again we will apply it on the fictional Acme Inc. software development team so you can see how elements of the Onion Model translate (and get expanded) by the Cultural Web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elements of the Culture Onion</title>
      <link>/elements-of-the-culture-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 22:43:16 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements-of-the-culture-onion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My last post gave a &lt;a href=&#34;/culture-re-introduction/&#34;&gt;brief explanation of what culture is&lt;/a&gt;, the main takeaway point being that culture is all around us on different levels. The next logical question is, “&lt;a href=&#34;/why-care-about-culture/&#34;&gt;Why should I care?&lt;/a&gt;” I&amp;rsquo;ll answer that in the next few weeks because we need to take a short detour – specifically, how would one analyse and assess the culture of a given group? The answer may lie in the culture onion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although cultures can be difficult to compartmentalise, try we must, and much smarter people before us have offered some suggestions. Let&amp;rsquo;s check them out and apply it on a fictional group – the Acme Inc. software development team._&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture - a re-introduction</title>
      <link>/culture-a-re-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 01:38:15 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/culture-a-re-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Culture’ as a term is a loaded word. Experts from different fields have their own definitions, which makes it that much harder to comprehend. It is also understandable when people react negatively as it gets bandied about. It’s used as a scapegoat – “Our product launch failed because we didn’t factor in the culture”, and often elicits eye-rolling – “We’ll boost company morale with our culture change programme!” It’s also a common phrase in job ads – “Come join us, we’ve got a great culture!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are any of them valid statements? I think it’s time to strip culture back down to basics, in order to understand how it affects us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
