<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coder Frontline</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Coder Frontline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 11:08:00 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>12 Days of Learning</title>
      <link>/12-days-of-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 11:08:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/12-days-of-learning/</guid>
      <description>The greatest challenge for developers who want to stay on the forefront of technology is the sheer amount of innovation happening everywhere. It is simply overwhelming for anyone to know everything. My advice for people starting out is to focus on one stack, e.g. React web apps, and get really comfortable with it so you build a solid technical foundation. It is still natural to feel like you&amp;rsquo;re falling behind when others talk about some cool tech they used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZERO60</title>
      <link>/zero60/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 07:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/zero60/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! Welcome to ZERO60 - a little company I set up to conduct Zumba Fitness classes.
My Facebook or Instagram page is the best place to see where I am teaching next and details of any livestreams I&amp;rsquo;m doing.
If I am doing a livestream right at this moment it will appear below, otherwise you will see a black box and that&amp;rsquo;s OK! Follow my Facebook or Instagram page so you know when my next one will be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrome&#39;s SameSite Cookie Changes are Breaking Apps</title>
      <link>/chromes-samesite-cookie-changes-are-breaking-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 21:36:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/chromes-samesite-cookie-changes-are-breaking-apps/</guid>
      <description>Updated 8 April 2020 with alternative regex if your OS or framework or app automatically adds the SameSite=Lax header to your session cookies. It is important to double check what your app is emitting so you can tailor the regex to suit!
 I just spent a good 6 hours of my life trying to debug a weird web app issue that I finally pinned down to the SameSite cookie attribute changes spearheaded by Google.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Team Brand</title>
      <link>/our-team-brand/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 22:08:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/our-team-brand/</guid>
      <description>One of my highlights at work in 2019 was taking the team through a Team Brand exercise. This is a culture definition team activity that I learned from a previous role. It is based on a simple premise: What words do you want other teams to use when describing us?
Team culture fascinates me but it often lives as a vague affirmation that &amp;ldquo;Yes, we want a good culture&amp;rdquo;. How does that translate into meanigful behaviours and actions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AppDynamics APM for .Net Apps Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>/appdynamics-apm-for-.net-apps-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 17:28:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/appdynamics-apm-for-.net-apps-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m getting involved with Cisco AppDynamics APM (Application Performance Monitoring) at work and have been finding lots of little tricks and gotchas with instrumenting ASP .Net web applications on Windows servers. I have compiled a list of quick tips that may help you set yourself up for APM bliss.
.Net Agent Installation The .Net Agent Setup on Windows is a breeze to go through. It even installs a Windows application called AppDynamics Agent Configuration that lets you easily re-configure the agent afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLS 1.2 support on .Net 4.5</title>
      <link>/tls-1.2-support-on-.net-4.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 14:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tls-1.2-support-on-.net-4.5/</guid>
      <description>Part of my job involves supporting legacy software running on older .Net Frameworks. There was a period of upheaval last year when support for TLS 1.0 was switched off by many payment processing gateways. A lot of online guides use this simple trick to force .Net 4.5 application to use TLS 1.2:
ServicePointManager.SecurityProtocol = SecurityProtocolType.Tls12; This turns out to be a bad move because the code will only support TLS 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireshark Capture Filter by Host IP</title>
      <link>/wireshark-capture-filter-by-host-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 13:28:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/wireshark-capture-filter-by-host-ip/</guid>
      <description>I keep forgetting this simple syntax and hopefully this will come in handy. In Wireshark you can specify a capture filter to only log traffic to/from a specific IP address with:
host {ipAddress}   Wireshark Capture Filter   I needed to use a capture filter because I was running captures on a low-spec server, and without a capture filter Wireshark eats up all the memory.
Related tip: Use nslookup to get the IP address that is resolved to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello from DevCamp</title>
      <link>/hello-from-devcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 17:28:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hello-from-devcamp/</guid>
      <description>Hello from DevCamp 2019 - Datacom&amp;rsquo;s premier developer unconference.
  Hello from DevCamp   Join us next year - check out Datacom Jobs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update SSL Cert on Azure App Service</title>
      <link>/update-ssl-cert-on-azure-app-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/update-ssl-cert-on-azure-app-service/</guid>
      <description>There are so many different tutorials on how to provision and install an SSL/TLS certificate on Azure App Services that I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write one that worked for me. I added some indicative timelines so you know how long each step may take. As a rule I recommend starting this process at least a week before the current certificate will expire.
Pre-requisites Find a different tutorial if you don&amp;rsquo;t have these exact components because your results may vary:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you eat a giant pumpkin?</title>
      <link>/how-do-you-eat-a-giant-pumpkin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 09:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-do-you-eat-a-giant-pumpkin/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a useful analogy I use to explain how to break a feature down into its unit tests. I am using it in a TDD (Test-Driven Development) workshop I&amp;rsquo;m conducting in my team. Putting aside the fact that giant pumpkins are mainly bred for show, this will hopefully help new programmers when they&amp;rsquo;re faced with any programming challenge. I created this analogy as an alternative to &amp;ldquo;How do you eat an elephant?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My static CMS site architecture</title>
      <link>/my-static-cms-site-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 15:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/my-static-cms-site-architecture/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned in my last post that I started 2019 by moving this blog off WordPress and into a Hugo static CMS set up. I will go into more detail about the particular approach I took to migrate the site over the next several posts. I will start the series off by quickly showing you the main architectural differences between a traditional CMS like WordPress and a modern static CMS like Hugo or Jekkyl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Beginnings</title>
      <link>/new-year-new-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new-year-new-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>A new year presents new opportunities to transform ourselves. New changes are afoot for this blog. This is the first new post since I migrated this blog from my old WordPress installation to Hugo static CMS.
Minimum Viable Product I still need to refine many aspects of the blog so what you see as of Dec 31st, 2018 will surely change. I am taking an Agile approach by launching with my MVP (Minimum Viable Product) to gauge interest and refine my product as I go along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Zumba helped me become a better Tech Lead</title>
      <link>/how-zumba-helped-me-become-a-better-tech-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 21:50:12 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-zumba-helped-me-become-a-better-tech-lead/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about some of the commonalities between Zumba instructors and Tech Leads in my last post. I have a few more points to add on, which will give you an idea of the multitude of skills required to be either.
Multitasking Zumba instructors are fierce multitaskers. Our main job is to dance to the music so that participants can follow along. But we also need to think ahead to what the next move is because we need to inform the class that the change is coming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do Tech Leads and Zumba instructors have in common?</title>
      <link>/what-do-tech-leads-and-zumba-instructors-have-in-common/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 15:25:58 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/what-do-tech-leads-and-zumba-instructors-have-in-common/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a part-time Zumba instructor since 2011 and I was a certified Les Mills BodyJam instructor for a few years before that. I recently looked back at my past year being a Tech Lead at Datacom and I can see many similarities with the necessary qualities of being either. I am in a very unique position since I have inhabited both roles, hence I wrote this post to illuminate some of the non-obvious ways a group fitness instructor creates an effective workout session, and how that ties in to be a great Tech Lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting My Functional Journey</title>
      <link>/starting-my-functional-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 12:44:45 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/starting-my-functional-journey/</guid>
      <description>I joined a new team as Tech Lead about 6 months ago. Rather than sit back and bark orders, it has become even more important to sharpen my technical skills. I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to start on my functional journey to become proficient in F# - the .Net functional programming language.
F# has been around for a long time but many from the C# camp have dismissed it as a niche language for the scientific and mathematic arena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context Switching Recovery Using A Diary</title>
      <link>/context-switching-recovery-using-a-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:12:11 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/context-switching-recovery-using-a-diary/</guid>
      <description>The term ‘context switching’ originated from the world of computing but has migrated into popular culture in relation to the wasted time caused by human multitasking. Context switching usually causes reduced productivity due to the effort of splitting focus over multiple tasks at once. This is something that most human brains are not good at. What can we do about it?
Our modern and busy lives force us to change our focus throughout the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest in the Best Tools You Can Afford</title>
      <link>/invest-in-the-best-tools-you-can-afford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 10:56:07 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/invest-in-the-best-tools-you-can-afford/</guid>
      <description>I recently bought a new steam iron. I’ve been wearing more business shirts to work lately, which resulted in an increased number of creased shirts every wash. I have a working steam iron and I only bought the new one because it was heavily discounted. My usual philosophy is to use a piece of equipment until it breaks before getting a replacement, but I had a niggling feeling that I needed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Open Door Policy Is Not Enough</title>
      <link>/the-open-door-policy-is-not-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 13:47:38 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-open-door-policy-is-not-enough/</guid>
      <description>I remember hearing the term open door policy when I joined my first company after university. It was touted as a morale-booster because we are free to bring up any concerns we have with our managers, or even managers higher up the food chain. I remember being impressed by the concept when it was explained to me, but I&amp;rsquo;m beginning to question if the open door policy is doing more harm than good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chess Master and The Gardener</title>
      <link>/the-chess-master-and-the-gardener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 21:32:57 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-chess-master-and-the-gardener/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love listening to podcasts to entertain my commute. I&amp;rsquo;ll at least learn something if I&amp;rsquo;m going to be stuck in traffic 200 hours a year. One of my subscriptions is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-tony-robbins-podcast/id1098413063?mt=2&#34;&gt;Tony Robbins Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, featuring the motivational guru interviewing a myriad of successful individuals. A recent episode that really resonated with me is a chat with General Stanley McChrystal and Chris Fussell, titled “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tonyrobbins.com/podcasts/becoming-extraordinary-leader/&#34;&gt;Becoming an extraordinary leader&lt;/a&gt;“. The interviewees served in the U.S. military for decades and have gained some insights into great leadership. An analogy the General used to describe leadership was the chess master and the gardener.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Little Things Matter</title>
      <link>/the-little-things-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 16:28:09 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-little-things-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a day off today after a stressful month. So I decided to treat myself to a massage to work out those tense shoulders I&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying around. But I saw something before the massage even started that reaffirmed my belief that the little things matter more than we appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humidity Monitor - Winter of Xamarin 2017</title>
      <link>/humidity-monitor-winter-of-xamarin-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 23:42:47 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/humidity-monitor-winter-of-xamarin-2017/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to announce that I won Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Winter of Xamarin competition this year with my Humidity Monitor App. Here&amp;rsquo;s my submission video:
The sanitised source code (with the keys and connection strings removed) is on my GitHub repo. Here&amp;rsquo;s a rough guide on how you can replicate the project and some ideas to extend it further:
Pre-requisites  A Raspberry Pi 3 running Windows 10 IoT Sense HAT module Recommended: 40-pin GPIO ribbon cable to keep some distance between the Pi and the Sense HAT because the Pi&amp;rsquo;s hot running temperature will affect Sense HAT readings (Optional) A Belkin WeMo Smart Switch or alternative smart switch that can connect to IFTTT (Optional) A dehumidifier that can be turned on from the switch (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Shortcuts Make Us Look Stupid</title>
      <link>/taking-shortcuts-make-us-look-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 22:24:11 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/taking-shortcuts-make-us-look-stupid/</guid>
      <description>I came across this error message when I was setting up a new Visual Studio Team Services build and found it quite funny. A valid ASP .Net Core project does not need a web.config file when it&amp;rsquo;s not hosted in IIS, and it definitely doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a wwwroot folder if it&amp;rsquo;s an API that does not serve static files.Error when running dotnet publish command
It made me reflect on my past choices when designing software solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact the World with impactNPO</title>
      <link>/impact-the-world-with-impactnpo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 22:10:19 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/impact-the-world-with-impactnpo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like doing charitable work. I feel that most of us live privileged lives, whether through circumstance or hard work. It’s always made sense to me that we have a moral imperative to help those who are less fortunate. I finally found a non-profit where I can apply my IT experience to help charitable organisations do just that and positively impact the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I Start Using Dotnet Core?</title>
      <link>/should-i-start-using-dotnet-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 12:35:36 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/should-i-start-using-dotnet-core/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote about my &lt;a href=&#34;/cutting-edge-technology-cuts/&#34;&gt;negative experiences with ASP .Net Core&lt;/a&gt; almost a year ago. I&amp;rsquo;m ready to reverse my opinion and think that ASP .Net Core is ready for primetime. I recently completed a multi-month project at work that primarily used ASP .Net Core and I had a positive experience. I share some thoughts and tips if you want to start using Dotnet Core (as it is sometimes called) beyond Hello World. These suggestions come from the perspective of a corporate software developer who is familiar with the full .Net framework and Visual Studio.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Pride</title>
      <link>/developer-pride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 04:48:12 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/developer-pride/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My development manager recently asked us for input on building an engineering culture at work. I semi-coined a new term: developer pride. The term has gotten &lt;a class=&#34;external-link&#34; href=&#34;http://codesqueeze.com/do-managers-prey-on-developer-pride/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;bad rep&lt;/a&gt; in the past, but I want to reclaim it in the same way the LGBT rights movement transformed the word &lt;em&gt;pride&lt;/em&gt; from the negative connotations of being a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_deadly_sins#Pride&#34;&gt;deadly sin&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theallusionist.org/allusionist/pride&#34;&gt;antidote to shame&lt;/a&gt;. So what does developer pride mean to me?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mob Programming: Is It Just a Fad?</title>
      <link>/mob-programming-is-it-just-a-fad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 15:00:14 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mob-programming-is-it-just-a-fad/</guid>
      <description>I first heard the term Mob Programming on a Hanselminutes podcast. I then got a closer look at it through Mark Pearl’s talk on the subject at an Agile Auckland Meetup. He even wrote a Leanpub book about Mob Programming. Mark is an Engineering Lead at MYOB and it’s great to hear him share his first-hand experience with running a mob team locally. I like the potential of Mob Programming but I&amp;rsquo;ve been pondering for the past week: Is it just a fad?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Becoming Blue-Collared Workers?</title>
      <link>/are-we-becoming-blue-collared-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 13:03:37 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/are-we-becoming-blue-collared-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are coders the next blue-collared job? This is the hypothesis Clive Thompson puts forward in his thought-provoking Wired piece &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2017/02/programming-is-the-new-blue-collar-job&#34;&gt;The Next Big Blue-Collar Job Is Coding&lt;/a&gt;. A knee-jerk reaction from IT professionals (read their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2017/02/programming-is-the-new-blue-collar-job/#article-comments&#34;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;) is to deny any possibility of that happening due to the years of training needed to get to their level. I certainly shared that first impression, partly because the term ‘blue-collared’ has negative connotations of being decidedly middle-class. I started thinking about this a bit more deeply when Clive wrote:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faking Extroversion: An Introvert&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>/faking-extroversion-an-introverts-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 14:40:01 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faking-extroversion-an-introverts-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was having a drink with a friend I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen in years when he confided that he&amp;rsquo;s having trouble making friends in a new city. He had moved there to be close to his partner, which meant that his social circle was limited to his partner&amp;rsquo;s social circle. This posed a problem for my friend whenever he had relationship issues, as he did not have nearby friends of his own. His main roadblock, he insisted, was his introversion. I can certainly relate to that as I am an introvert myself. However, I recognize the value of having a strong social support network, which inherently requires some extroversion to build. I faced the same issue when I moved to New Zealand alone and had to make a concerted effort to fake extroversion. I decided to share some of my techniques with this friend and it inspired me to write this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective 2016</title>
      <link>/retrospective-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 19:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/retrospective-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a retrospective for my entire 2016 year. While the practice of retrospectives is commonplace in Agile projects, the act itself can be found in many areas in our lives. Counting our blessings, gratitude journals, and even some forms of meditation are based on past reflections so that we can prepare for the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Interview Questions #26</title>
      <link>/good-interview-questions-#26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 20:45:24 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/good-interview-questions-#26/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve encountered all sorts of interview questions, mostly on the receiving end but some as part of the interviewing team myself. I will elaborate on some good and bad interview questions, at least in my humble opinion. The numbers are random fun – I don’t have 25 other examples on this blog (yet).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Excerpt: Impossible to Ignore</title>
      <link>/book-excerpt-impossible-to-ignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 21:22:03 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/book-excerpt-impossible-to-ignore/</guid>
      <description>Is your presentation impossible to ignore? I’ve sat through many presentations in my lifetime, and I expect to sit through quite a few more before I die. It’s astonishing how many technical presentations are treated as information dumps, with no intention to persuade or get audiences to improve their ways. People get bored, and I frequently see smartphones whipped out in conference rooms. I have been guilty of giving such presentations before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate On-Boarding for Early Success</title>
      <link>/deliberate-on-boarding-for-early-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 10:03:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deliberate-on-boarding-for-early-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On-boarding programmes, also known as induction programmes, are the set of activities designed to get a new hire up and running in the organisation as soon as possible. I discussed a few types of &lt;a href=&#34;/induction-programmes-new-hires/&#34;&gt;induction programmes&lt;/a&gt; last week. I will share my own experiences with on-boarding below, including the elements that go into making an effective plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induction Programmes for New Hires</title>
      <link>/induction-programmes-for-new-hires/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 10:23:27 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/induction-programmes-for-new-hires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few tech companies give much thought to formal induction programmes for new employees. It does not seem to give much benefit at first glance, since it happens irregularly. I have experienced both well-structured and informal induction programmes, and I can wholeheartedly say I prefer the former.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web API Practices: Controller Unit Tests</title>
      <link>/web-api-practices-controller-unit-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 20:58:37 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/web-api-practices-controller-unit-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sharing some of the best practices that I used in a recent ASP .Net Web API and MVC project. I recently gave a presentation to my team on the Top 5 Web API &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/span&gt; Practices, and I continue the series by discussing controller unit tests. I struck out the word ‘Best&#39; intentionally. There are so many best practices out there. These practices happened to work very well for this project, but your mileage may vary. However, I think most people understand the value of unit testing, and I’m here to show you some tips in regards to writing controller unit tests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web API Practices: Hypermedia API Responses</title>
      <link>/web-api-practices-hypermedia-api-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 17:44:36 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/web-api-practices-hypermedia-api-responses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sharing some of the best practices that I used in a recent ASP .Net Web API and MVC project. I recently gave a presentation to my team on the Top 5 Web API &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/span&gt; Practices, and I continue the series by discussing Hypermedia API responses. I struck out the word ‘Best&#39; intentionally. There are so many best practices out there but not all of them will suit your unique circumstance, especially in regards to Hypermedia API design. These practices happened to work very well for this project, but your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web API Practices: Consistent Response Format</title>
      <link>/web-api-practices-consistent-response-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 09:43:56 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/web-api-practices-consistent-response-format/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sharing some of the best practices that I used in a recent ASP .Net Web API and MVC project. I recently gave a presentation to my team on the Top 5 Web API &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/span&gt; Practices, and I continue the series by discussing AutoMapper this week. I struck out the word ‘Best&#39; intentionally. There are so many best practices out there but not all of them will suit your unique circumstance. These practices happened to work very well for this project, but your mileage may vary. Consistent response formats, however, are pretty much universal and something that all of us should be doing already.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Hiatus</title>
      <link>/another-hiatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 22:48:42 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/another-hiatus/</guid>
      <description>I am stepping away from the frontline again to finish up my second assignment. I will be back sometime in October to finish my series on Web API practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisited: Why Care About Culture?</title>
      <link>/revisited-why-care-about-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 11:41:21 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/revisited-why-care-about-culture/</guid>
      <description>This coder is stepping away from the front line for another week while he takes a well-deserved holiday on the Indonesian destination of Bali. Instead, I will link to an article from the archives and add some new thoughts on it.
This week I revisit my post on why we should care about culture. I put forward my argument that we should pay close attention to culture as it affects more than just whether people have work drinks on a Friday afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisited: Cutting-Edge Technology Cuts</title>
      <link>/revisited-cutting-edge-technology-cuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 11:25:28 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/revisited-cutting-edge-technology-cuts/</guid>
      <description>This coder is stepping away from the front line for two weeks while he takes a well-deserved holiday on the Indonesian destination of Bali. Instead, I will link to an article from the archives and add some new thoughts on it.
This week I revisit my post Cutting-Edge Technology Cuts, where I lambasted ASP .Net Core RC1 for its weak tooling support and how I rolled back to ASP .Net 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web API Practices: AutoMapper for Object-Object Mapping</title>
      <link>/web-api-practices-automapper-for-object-object-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 14:51:18 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/web-api-practices-automapper-for-object-object-mapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sharing some of the best practices that I used in a recent ASP .Net Web API and MVC project. I recently gave a presentation to my team on the Top 5 Web API &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: line-through;&#34;&gt;Best&lt;/span&gt; Practices, and I continue the series by discussing AutoMapper this week. I struck out the word ‘Best&#39; intentionally. There are so many best practices out there but not all of them will suit your unique circumstance. These practices happened to work very well for this project, but your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web API Practices: Use Dependency Injection</title>
      <link>/web-api-practices-use-dependency-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 10:18:20 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/web-api-practices-use-dependency-injection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a web project for the past year that used both ASP .Net (4.5.2) Web API and MVC. The Web API provides a foundation for flexible data access, while MVC uses it to power a rich web application. I recently gave a presentation to my team on the Top 5 Web API &lt;del&gt;Best&lt;/del&gt; Practices, and I will reproduce portions of it over the next five entries. I struck out the word ‘Best&#39; intentionally. There are so many best practices out there but not all of them will suit your unique circumstance. These practices happened to work very well for this project, and we&amp;rsquo;ll start with a popular one - dependency injection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Date Picker: Unit Tests</title>
      <link>/smart-date-picker-unit-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 22:13:02 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/smart-date-picker-unit-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally add some unit tests for my date range bumper logic. I based it on my earlier blog &lt;a href=&#34;/smart-date-picker-requirements/&#34;&gt;post on test cases&lt;/a&gt; with some additions. I subsequently found bugs that I wouldn’t have found otherwise. I also added FRP code to differentiate between start and end date selection, which I’ll briefly talk about later. But first, a community service message regarding unit tests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Week Posting Hiatus</title>
      <link>/two-week-posting-hiatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 21:11:22 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/two-week-posting-hiatus/</guid>
      <description>I am taking a two week hiatus from blogging as I need to finish my first Marketing Management assignment. I am doing a marketing study on 1Above the flight drink company. The study of product marketing is a new subject for me, and so I have quite a bit to catch up on.
Photo credit: Pierre J. via VisualHunt / CC BY-NC-SA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Date Picker: Selecting and bumping dates</title>
      <link>/smart-date-picker-selecting-and-bumping-dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 13:18:33 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/smart-date-picker-selecting-and-bumping-dates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a direct continuation of the &lt;a href=&#34;/smart-date-picker-period-type-frp-primitives/&#34;&gt;last post on using FRP primitives&lt;/a&gt; to model changing the period type. I will jump straight into the next part of adding more smart date picker functionality. You might want to review the &lt;a href=&#34;/?s=smart+date+picker&#34;&gt;entire series&lt;/a&gt; on making a smart date picker if this is your first visit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Date Picker: Changing the period type using FRP Primitives</title>
      <link>/smart-date-picker-changing-the-period-type-using-frp-primitives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 15:05:55 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/smart-date-picker-changing-the-period-type-using-frp-primitives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve faffed about at the fringes of functional reactive programming (FRP) for a while now, but I think it’s time to take a cold plunge into actually using some Sodium FRP primitives. FRP primitives are the fundamental operations (methods or functions) that make up the core of FRP. What makes them primitive is that they cannot be expressed using any other combination of operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My objective over the next few weeks is to reimagine the smart date picker’s data flow/dependency diagram by using FRP primitives. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SodiumFRP/sodium&#34;&gt;Sodium&lt;/a&gt;, the library I am using for this lesson, has ten FRP primitives. There isn’t enough space here to explain each one in detail (I recommend the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manning.com/books/functional-reactive-programming&#34;&gt;Functional Reactive Programming&lt;/a&gt; for this purpose), but I will briefly introduce them as I go along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I start implementing the changes to the period type.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Date Picker: Cells and Streams</title>
      <link>/smart-date-picker-cells-and-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 13:43:58 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/smart-date-picker-cells-and-streams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I covered the &lt;a href=&#34;/smart-date-picker-requirements/&#34;&gt;requirements of the smart date picker&lt;/a&gt; in my last post, which ended with a data flow diagram. Today I aim to translate that conceptual view to primitives within &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SodiumFRP/sodium&#34;&gt;Sodium, a functional reactive programming (FRP) library&lt;/a&gt; supported on multiple languages. The only types in Sodium are Cells and Streams. I will attempt to provide a brief explanation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Date Picker: Requirements and Test Cases</title>
      <link>/smart-date-picker-requirements-and-test-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 22:49:16 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/smart-date-picker-requirements-and-test-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hinted three weeks ago that I wished to &lt;a href=&#34;/events-are-evil/&#34;&gt;learn functional reactive programming&lt;/a&gt; by implementing a smart date picker. Since then I shared my &lt;a href=&#34;/first-impressions-functional-reactive-programming-sodium/&#34;&gt;impressions on the book&lt;/a&gt; but have yet to delve into actually working on the control. I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much time to read the book (curse you, Uncharted 4), and so I am still a bit clueless about where to start. It&amp;rsquo;s time to take the plunge though, and I will outline my stumbles through thinking about business requirements from a data perspective. In this post I flesh out the requirements and test cases a bit more and think about how they rely on each other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Impressions Functional Reactive Programming with Sodium</title>
      <link>/more-impressions-functional-reactive-programming-with-sodium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 12:27:09 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/more-impressions-functional-reactive-programming-with-sodium/</guid>
      <description>I shared a couple of my first impressions reading the Functional Reactive Programming book, and I am back with more after going a bit further with the book. I am spending this weekend in beautiful Queenstown, New Zealand for the Queenstown Winter Festival so this post is shorter than usual.
Book Organisation This book is not a ‘cookbook’ – it is not a collection of code recipes you can read and then easily apply in your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Impressions Functional Reactive Programming with Sodium</title>
      <link>/first-impressions-functional-reactive-programming-with-sodium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 12:26:07 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/first-impressions-functional-reactive-programming-with-sodium/</guid>
      <description>This is part of an ongoing series where I review the book Functional Reactive Programming by Stephen Blackheath and Anthony Jones. Kindly note that anything I write here may be incorrect and not indicative of the author’s intent. After all, making mistakes is the mother of learning and this book review is meant to be a truthful reflection of my own experiences grasping a new concept. The review copy I received was version 11 in their Manning’s Early Access Program, so the book’s contents may differ at the time of publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Events Are Evil</title>
      <link>/events-are-evil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 12:57:28 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events-are-evil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Events are evil. Yes, that is quite the incendiary statement to make. To clarify, I don’t mean events in the physical world like rock concerts and art festivals. I am referring to the common event handling patterns most programmers are familiar with, such as button click event handlers and JavaScript callbacks. They are popular because they are simple to set up – most languages support some form of asynchronous event handling out of the box. However, its prevalence does not mean it is perfect, and I have recently come across a different event handling paradigm that promises to rehabilitate events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Software on Windows 10 IoT</title>
      <link>/developing-software-on-windows-10-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 09:35:42 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/developing-software-on-windows-10-iot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s taken me awhile to get into the Internet of Things due to my lack of knowledge around interfacing with the hardware. Luckily, developing software on Windows 10 IoT is almost a breeze for .Net developers thanks to Microsoft’s great tooling support. There are a lot of great tutorials online so I will focus instead on highlighting unique aspects about programming applications for the Raspberry Pi 3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Windows 10 IoT on Raspberry Pi 3</title>
      <link>/configuring-windows-10-iot-on-raspberry-pi-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 09:06:07 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/configuring-windows-10-iot-on-raspberry-pi-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Configuring Windows 10 IoT is the next logical step after &lt;a href=&#34;/installing-windows-10-iot/&#34;&gt;OS installation&lt;/a&gt;. These tips should apply to any of the boards supported by Windows 10 IoT, but I will focus on the Raspberry Pi 3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Windows 10 IoT on Raspberry Pi 3</title>
      <link>/installing-windows-10-iot-on-raspberry-pi-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 09:22:28 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installing-windows-10-iot-on-raspberry-pi-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Installing Windows 10 IoT on a Raspberry Pi 3 can be quite easy… if you take care of a few things up front. I’m wording this blog post from a total newbie’s perspective – someone who might know how to write software, but is taking their first dip into doing IoT in general and Raspberry Pi 3 in particular. If that fits your profile, keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 10 IoT on Raspberry Pi 3 – A Toe Dip</title>
      <link>/windows-10-iot-on-raspberry-pi-3-a-toe-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 11:04:32 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/windows-10-iot-on-raspberry-pi-3-a-toe-dip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being a software engineering graduate, I’ve always looked at hardware as the other side of the river from me. It sounds a bit surprising considering my first job was at Agilent (now &lt;a href=&#34;http://jobs.keysight.com/country-malaysia/#section-overview&#34;&gt;Keysight&lt;/a&gt;), a top electronics measurement company, but I’ve always treated the hardware component of my work with a little apprehension. However, the Internet of Things (IoT) is becoming very prolific and it’s no longer something I can easily ignore. I’ve thus decided to start dipping my toes in that cold, cold river, beginning with installing Windows 10 IoT on a Raspberry Pi 3. I will share my experiences as I learn more about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techweek AKL 14-22 May 2016</title>
      <link>/techweek-akl-14-22-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 03:55:08 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/techweek-akl-14-22-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first ever &lt;a href=&#34;http://techweek.co.nz/&#34;&gt;Techweek AKL&lt;/a&gt; starts in less than a week and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to attend some of the events. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great start to building NZ&amp;rsquo;s tech resources. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s no TechCrunch Disrupt but this will definitely start us down that path. However I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s very well publicised as I only found out about it while glancing through the last &lt;a href=&#34;http://ourauckland.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/&#34;&gt;Our Auckland newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. Consider this my small part in raising its visibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Lenses: How Strategy is Formulated</title>
      <link>/strategy-lenses-how-strategy-is-formulated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 01:18:46 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/strategy-lenses-how-strategy-is-formulated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do a quick add-on to last week’s post about the many &lt;a href=&#34;/definitions-of-strategy/&#34;&gt;definitions of strategy&lt;/a&gt;, specifically: How is strategy formulated? Again, many perspectives abound and one approach is the strategy lenses, as found in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1X1hV7x&#34;&gt;Exploring Strategy 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; edition&lt;/a&gt;. In it, the authors present various ways of comprehending strategy development, and they can be loosely linked to &lt;a href=&#34;/definitions-of-strategy/&#34;&gt;Mintzberg’s 5 P’s of strategy&lt;/a&gt; I covered last week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clash of Culture - MediaWorks and Mark Weldon Part Ways</title>
      <link>/clash-of-culture-mediaworks-and-mark-weldon-part-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 01:00:25 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clash-of-culture-mediaworks-and-mark-weldon-part-ways/</guid>
      <description>A clash of culture happens when cultures don&amp;rsquo;t mesh - and the resulting fireworks can be very dangerous. It gives further reason to care about culture and how one&amp;rsquo;s personal culture can affect the entire organisation. Some choice excerpts from NZ Herald - 4 May 2016 article on Mark Weldon&amp;rsquo;s resignation (all **emphasis **is mine):
 “People in that company actually love that company. The issue for Mark is that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a cultural fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Many Definitions of Strategy</title>
      <link>/the-many-definitions-of-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 02:38:17 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-many-definitions-of-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is strategy in a business context? That is an even more elusive question than &lt;a href=&#34;/culture-re-introduction/&#34;&gt;what culture is&lt;/a&gt;. I always thought strategy meant market positioning, but my recent academic foray has exposed me to the many definitions of strategy. I list them below, and while some may contradict another, they are in fact all correct. How can that be, you ask? I reckon it is similar to light and sound, which can behave like a wave or a particle under different circumstances (the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave%E2%80%93particle_duality&#34;&gt;wave-particle duality&lt;/a&gt;). To paraphrase Einstein, the different definitions of strategy present “&lt;em&gt;contradictory pictures of reality; separately neither of them fully explains the phenomena of”&lt;/em&gt; strategy_, “but together they do”_.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting-Edge Technology Cuts</title>
      <link>/cutting-edge-technology-cuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 04:51:09 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cutting-edge-technology-cuts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bring you a cautionary tale this week about the dangers of using cutting-edge technology and how it can cut you. Like many programmers I get excited with the prospect of using new technology, frameworks, or languages – especially for commercial uses. It’s one thing to try stuff out on the weekend and build tutorial projects, but it’s another ball game to actually build something someone would buy. So I rubbed my hands with glee when the opportunity arose to redesign a web app that was written in ASP .Net MVC 3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Theory on Success - How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big</title>
      <link>/a-theory-on-success-how-to-fail-at-almost-everything-and-still-win-big/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 04:52:27 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-theory-on-success-how-to-fail-at-almost-everything-and-still-win-big/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Qf49Xg&#34;&gt;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big: Kind of the Story of My Life&lt;/a&gt; is the title of an excellent book about success (or lack thereof!) by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Scott Adams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt; creator and frequent writer on his personal blog. I’ve been an avid reader of his for years, and have read his non-Dilbert fiction books (&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1Qf4lWq&#34;&gt;God’s Debris&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1SSEq8P&#34;&gt;The Religion War&lt;/a&gt;) as well. What I enjoy most about Scott’s writing style is the concise manner he puts his points across. It’s an important skill to have when trying to make readers laugh in 3 comic panels, and he puts it to good use in his writing. The following is a brief overview of the key points I took away from his book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Care About Culture</title>
      <link>/why-care-about-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 07:43:23 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-care-about-culture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last 3 posts I have &lt;a href=&#34;/culture-re-introduction/&#34;&gt;re-introduced culture&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;/elements-culture-onion/&#34;&gt;explained it as an onion&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;/cultural-web/&#34;&gt;explored the cultural web&lt;/a&gt;. It’s now crunch time – why care about culture at all? Culture is dynamic and monolithic, made up of deeply-held assumptions and embedded in corporate DNA. Many authors have tried to discredit the idea of cultural change as a strategic move. They recommend tailoring strategies and tactics to fit the existing culture instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why care about culture? I will skip the textbook answers this time and share my personal view. I care about culture because it affects how well I can do my job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Web</title>
      <link>/cultural-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 02:35:26 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cultural-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Cultural Web Analysis is another useful tool that helps tease out the constituent parts of an organisation’s culture. It builds upon the &lt;a href=&#34;/elements-culture-onion/&#34;&gt;Onion Model of Culture mentioned previously&lt;/a&gt;, but has more concrete classifications that I found helpful. The Cultural Web was introduced by Gerry Johnson and Kevan Scholes, who were also writers of the excellent Exploring Strategy textbook I used for my Strategic Management course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again we will apply it on the fictional Acme Inc. software development team so you can see how elements of the Onion Model translate (and get expanded) by the Cultural Web.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posting Schedule</title>
      <link>/posting-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 22:36:42 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posting-schedule/</guid>
      <description>The posting schedule for this blog is about once a week. I set aside about 4 hours a week to work on the blog, and this week I&amp;rsquo;m using that time to approve a new logo through Mike on Fiverr and update some site elements based on the new graphics.
My posts on culture resume next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elements of the Culture Onion</title>
      <link>/elements-of-the-culture-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 22:43:16 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements-of-the-culture-onion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My last post gave a &lt;a href=&#34;/culture-re-introduction/&#34;&gt;brief explanation of what culture is&lt;/a&gt;, the main takeaway point being that culture is all around us on different levels. The next logical question is, “&lt;a href=&#34;/why-care-about-culture/&#34;&gt;Why should I care?&lt;/a&gt;” I&amp;rsquo;ll answer that in the next few weeks because we need to take a short detour – specifically, how would one analyse and assess the culture of a given group? The answer may lie in the culture onion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although cultures can be difficult to compartmentalise, try we must, and much smarter people before us have offered some suggestions. Let&amp;rsquo;s check them out and apply it on a fictional group – the Acme Inc. software development team._&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture - a re-introduction</title>
      <link>/culture-a-re-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 01:38:15 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/culture-a-re-introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;‘Culture’ as a term is a loaded word. Experts from different fields have their own definitions, which makes it that much harder to comprehend. It is also understandable when people react negatively as it gets bandied about. It’s used as a scapegoat – “Our product launch failed because we didn’t factor in the culture”, and often elicits eye-rolling – “We’ll boost company morale with our culture change programme!” It’s also a common phrase in job ads – “Come join us, we’ve got a great culture!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are any of them valid statements? I think it’s time to strip culture back down to basics, in order to understand how it affects us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another Tech blog?</title>
      <link>/yet-another-tech-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 15:00:53 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/yet-another-tech-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh no – not another one! Yes, I’ll be the first to acknowledge that there are probably enough programming and tech blogs out there. I’m doing this because I believe I have a unique perspective to share that you’ll be interested in. Coder on the Frontline is a blog focused around the realities of commercial software development today – think missed deadlines, incomplete requirements, Agile fanatics, and that latest buzzword ‘DevOps’. I can see you nodding your head already.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
