<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Coder Frontline</title>
    <link>/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Coder Frontline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Beginnings</title>
      <link>/new-year-new-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/new-year-new-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>A new year presents new opportunities to transform ourselves. New changes are afoot for this blog. This is the first new post since I migrated this blog from my old WordPress installation to Hugo static CMS.
Minimum Viable Product I still need to refine many aspects of the blog so what you see as of Dec 31st, 2018 will surely change. I am taking an Agile approach by launching with my MVP (Minimum Viable Product) to gauge interest and refine my product as I go along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context Switching Recovery Using A Diary</title>
      <link>/context-switching-recovery-using-a-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 14:12:11 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/context-switching-recovery-using-a-diary/</guid>
      <description>The term ‘context switching’ originated from the world of computing but has migrated into popular culture in relation to the wasted time caused by human multitasking. Context switching usually causes reduced productivity due to the effort of splitting focus over multiple tasks at once. This is something that most human brains are not good at. What can we do about it?
Our modern and busy lives force us to change our focus throughout the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Shortcuts Make Us Look Stupid</title>
      <link>/taking-shortcuts-make-us-look-stupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 22:24:11 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/taking-shortcuts-make-us-look-stupid/</guid>
      <description>I came across this error message when I was setting up a new Visual Studio Team Services build and found it quite funny. A valid ASP .Net Core project does not need a web.config file when it&amp;rsquo;s not hosted in IIS, and it definitely doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a wwwroot folder if it&amp;rsquo;s an API that does not serve static files.Error when running dotnet publish command
It made me reflect on my past choices when designing software solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact the World with impactNPO</title>
      <link>/impact-the-world-with-impactnpo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 22:10:19 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/impact-the-world-with-impactnpo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like doing charitable work. I feel that most of us live privileged lives, whether through circumstance or hard work. It’s always made sense to me that we have a moral imperative to help those who are less fortunate. I finally found a non-profit where I can apply my IT experience to help charitable organisations do just that and positively impact the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are We Becoming Blue-Collared Workers?</title>
      <link>/are-we-becoming-blue-collared-workers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 13:03:37 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/are-we-becoming-blue-collared-workers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are coders the next blue-collared job? This is the hypothesis Clive Thompson puts forward in his thought-provoking Wired piece &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2017/02/programming-is-the-new-blue-collar-job&#34;&gt;The Next Big Blue-Collar Job Is Coding&lt;/a&gt;. A knee-jerk reaction from IT professionals (read their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/2017/02/programming-is-the-new-blue-collar-job/#article-comments&#34;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt;) is to deny any possibility of that happening due to the years of training needed to get to their level. I certainly shared that first impression, partly because the term ‘blue-collared’ has negative connotations of being decidedly middle-class. I started thinking about this a bit more deeply when Clive wrote:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrospective 2016</title>
      <link>/retrospective-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 19:25:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/retrospective-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a retrospective for my entire 2016 year. While the practice of retrospectives is commonplace in Agile projects, the act itself can be found in many areas in our lives. Counting our blessings, gratitude journals, and even some forms of meditation are based on past reflections so that we can prepare for the future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Hiatus</title>
      <link>/another-hiatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 22:48:42 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/another-hiatus/</guid>
      <description>I am stepping away from the frontline again to finish up my second assignment. I will be back sometime in October to finish my series on Web API practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Week Posting Hiatus</title>
      <link>/two-week-posting-hiatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 21:11:22 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/two-week-posting-hiatus/</guid>
      <description>I am taking a two week hiatus from blogging as I need to finish my first Marketing Management assignment. I am doing a marketing study on 1Above the flight drink company. The study of product marketing is a new subject for me, and so I have quite a bit to catch up on.
Photo credit: Pierre J. via VisualHunt / CC BY-NC-SA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Windows 10 IoT on Raspberry Pi 3</title>
      <link>/installing-windows-10-iot-on-raspberry-pi-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 09:22:28 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/installing-windows-10-iot-on-raspberry-pi-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Installing Windows 10 IoT on a Raspberry Pi 3 can be quite easy… if you take care of a few things up front. I’m wording this blog post from a total newbie’s perspective – someone who might know how to write software, but is taking their first dip into doing IoT in general and Raspberry Pi 3 in particular. If that fits your profile, keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Techweek AKL 14-22 May 2016</title>
      <link>/techweek-akl-14-22-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 03:55:08 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/techweek-akl-14-22-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first ever &lt;a href=&#34;http://techweek.co.nz/&#34;&gt;Techweek AKL&lt;/a&gt; starts in less than a week and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to attend some of the events. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great start to building NZ&amp;rsquo;s tech resources. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s no TechCrunch Disrupt but this will definitely start us down that path. However I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s very well publicised as I only found out about it while glancing through the last &lt;a href=&#34;http://ourauckland.aucklandcouncil.govt.nz/&#34;&gt;Our Auckland newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. Consider this my small part in raising its visibility.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posting Schedule</title>
      <link>/posting-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 22:36:42 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posting-schedule/</guid>
      <description>The posting schedule for this blog is about once a week. I set aside about 4 hours a week to work on the blog, and this week I&amp;rsquo;m using that time to approve a new logo through Mike on Fiverr and update some site elements based on the new graphics.
My posts on culture resume next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet another Tech blog?</title>
      <link>/yet-another-tech-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 15:00:53 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/yet-another-tech-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh no – not another one! Yes, I’ll be the first to acknowledge that there are probably enough programming and tech blogs out there. I’m doing this because I believe I have a unique perspective to share that you’ll be interested in. Coder on the Frontline is a blog focused around the realities of commercial software development today – think missed deadlines, incomplete requirements, Agile fanatics, and that latest buzzword ‘DevOps’. I can see you nodding your head already.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
