<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy on Coder Frontline</title>
    <link>/categories/strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strategy on Coder Frontline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 01:18:46 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strategy Lenses: How Strategy is Formulated</title>
      <link>/strategy-lenses-how-strategy-is-formulated/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 01:18:46 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/strategy-lenses-how-strategy-is-formulated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to do a quick add-on to last week’s post about the many &lt;a href=&#34;/definitions-of-strategy/&#34;&gt;definitions of strategy&lt;/a&gt;, specifically: How is strategy formulated? Again, many perspectives abound and one approach is the strategy lenses, as found in &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1X1hV7x&#34;&gt;Exploring Strategy 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; edition&lt;/a&gt;. In it, the authors present various ways of comprehending strategy development, and they can be loosely linked to &lt;a href=&#34;/definitions-of-strategy/&#34;&gt;Mintzberg’s 5 P’s of strategy&lt;/a&gt; I covered last week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clash of Culture - MediaWorks and Mark Weldon Part Ways</title>
      <link>/clash-of-culture-mediaworks-and-mark-weldon-part-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 01:00:25 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/clash-of-culture-mediaworks-and-mark-weldon-part-ways/</guid>
      <description>A clash of culture happens when cultures don&amp;rsquo;t mesh - and the resulting fireworks can be very dangerous. It gives further reason to care about culture and how one&amp;rsquo;s personal culture can affect the entire organisation. Some choice excerpts from NZ Herald - 4 May 2016 article on Mark Weldon&amp;rsquo;s resignation (all **emphasis **is mine):
 “People in that company actually love that company. The issue for Mark is that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a cultural fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Many Definitions of Strategy</title>
      <link>/the-many-definitions-of-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 02:38:17 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-many-definitions-of-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What is strategy in a business context? That is an even more elusive question than &lt;a href=&#34;/culture-re-introduction/&#34;&gt;what culture is&lt;/a&gt;. I always thought strategy meant market positioning, but my recent academic foray has exposed me to the many definitions of strategy. I list them below, and while some may contradict another, they are in fact all correct. How can that be, you ask? I reckon it is similar to light and sound, which can behave like a wave or a particle under different circumstances (the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave%E2%80%93particle_duality&#34;&gt;wave-particle duality&lt;/a&gt;). To paraphrase Einstein, the different definitions of strategy present “&lt;em&gt;contradictory pictures of reality; separately neither of them fully explains the phenomena of”&lt;/em&gt; strategy_, “but together they do”_.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
