<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agile on Coder Frontline</title>
    <link>/categories/agile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agile on Coder Frontline</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-nz</language>
    <copyright>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 22:10:19 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/agile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Impact the World with impactNPO</title>
      <link>/impact-the-world-with-impactnpo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 22:10:19 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/impact-the-world-with-impactnpo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I like doing charitable work. I feel that most of us live privileged lives, whether through circumstance or hard work. It’s always made sense to me that we have a moral imperative to help those who are less fortunate. I finally found a non-profit where I can apply my IT experience to help charitable organisations do just that and positively impact the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate On-Boarding for Early Success</title>
      <link>/deliberate-on-boarding-for-early-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 10:03:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deliberate-on-boarding-for-early-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On-boarding programmes, also known as induction programmes, are the set of activities designed to get a new hire up and running in the organisation as soon as possible. I discussed a few types of &lt;a href=&#34;/induction-programmes-new-hires/&#34;&gt;induction programmes&lt;/a&gt; last week. I will share my own experiences with on-boarding below, including the elements that go into making an effective plan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induction Programmes for New Hires</title>
      <link>/induction-programmes-for-new-hires/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 10:23:27 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/induction-programmes-for-new-hires/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few tech companies give much thought to formal induction programmes for new employees. It does not seem to give much benefit at first glance, since it happens irregularly. I have experienced both well-structured and informal induction programmes, and I can wholeheartedly say I prefer the former.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
